Along with your considerations for what you'll want to buy as a telescope, you'll also want to spend some time wondering what you're going to look at.
How you're going to find it.
This is a very inexpensive and wonderful device called a planisphere.
This shows what stars are up at what time of night.
It's very simple to use.
You find your date on the outside.
This ring goes to set for what time it is.
Put the time on the date and you have a complete picture of what's up in the night sky at that time.
This one's for northern hemisphere, they're also made for people for the southern hemisphere.
Be sure and get the right one for your hemisphere.
Another one, go to your local book store, find atlas cards, Peterson's Field Guide to the Stars and planets, Norton's Guide to the Stars.
There are several excellent books, but you'll want to know what you want to look at with your telescope before you actually purchase the telescope.
There may be some advantages that you don't know until you know what you want to study.